グオ グルルル…
グオー グルルル
だあー あー
えーん えーん
ガアアー
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね) を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Ruler of the Wild Forest
How awful!
何ということに
直すったって こいつは
新しく作った方が早ええな
We could try fixing it, but it would be
quicker just to make a new one.
Some person is to blame after all.
やはり誰かが…
Maybe we oughta get out of here quick.
もう 早く戻った方がいいんじゃないか？
I'm afraid Mutikapa-sama might jump out
on us at any moment.
いつムティカパ様が
出てくるかと思うと…
Hey, what the heck do you think
we came out here for?
おいおい　何しに来たつもりなんだよ
But this is freaking us out!
でも おっかねえだろ
Especially when you think of what happened
to the people over in Hitta Village.
ヒッタの集落の話を聞いちまうとなあ
Mutikapa-sama sleeps during the daylight hours.
ムティカパ様は
明るい間は眠っておられるよ
She is nocturnal?
夜行性 ですか？
That's what I'm saying!
だとよー
んなビクビクしなくても平気だって
I'm telling ya you don't have to be so on edge!
今みたいな大声を出さなければな
As long as she doesn't hear anyone
speaking in loud voices like now.
Excuse me...
あの
Are you sure you're feeling well?
体の方は本当にいいんですか？
Oh, right, you'd be better off and
heading back soon, Kid.
おお　あんちゃんは早く戻った方がいいぜ
This'll aggravate your injuries, won't it?
傷に響くだろ
I am fine. Please allow me to assist you.
いえ
体はもう大丈夫です
手伝わせてください
Well, I don't really mind, but still...
そらかまわねえけどよ
I want to help in some way.
何か手伝いたいんです
うい
All right! Then I guess we can
count on you too, huh?
よーし んじゃあ頼むとすっか
Yes.
はい
えい
よい しょっと
There we go...
Giver of life, Ie, divine Nayalaon,
anikshete, yatikel, we offer to you...
命たるイェネ・アラオンカミ・
アニクシェテ・ヤティケル
願い奉り候　はあ
クェセ・トゥスクル・
ポトゥム・ソトゥカイ
Kuese, Tuskuru, potsuum sotookai...
Now...
これで
If only it will be enough to calm
Mutikapa-sama's anger...
ムティカパ様の怒りが鎮まってくれれば
Eruruu, what were those words
she spoke just now?
エルルゥ
今の言葉は？
It was a prayer of thanks to Divine Yahnaun.
ヤーナゥン・カミへの
感謝の祈りなんです
Thanks?
感謝？
We have received blessings from the forest in
the form of food, medicine and other things.
私たちは 食べ物とかお薬とか
森の恵みをいただいているんです
That's why we're grateful.
ですから
Yet you live in fear of the
forest master's wrath?
だが
森の主の怒りに
触れてしまったという訳か
はあ　どうして こんなことに…
How could this have happened?
イエー　ハハハ…
ま 待てよ
Wait up!
Hey, easy there, you three.
おーらおら お前ら　もう日が暮れるぞ
It's getting dark out. Now go home.
うちに戻れ
And make sure to close the door
and keep the noise down.
ちゃんと戸を閉めて 静かにしてるのよ
Thanks for all the hard work today, Chief.
村長 お疲れ様でした
My pleasure. I trust nothing
happened here, right?
ああ　こっちは何も無かったね？
No, everything went just fine.
ええ 何事も無く
I'm so hungry, Honey.
母ちゃん 腹減ったあ
You need to be a little more aware of
the crisis we're dealing with!
あんたはもうちょっと
危機感ってものを持ちなさいな
-エッヘッヘッヘ…
-ウフフフ
You two head home quickly now too. It should
give your families some peace of mind.
あ お前たちも早く家に戻って
家族を安心させてやるとええ
Yes, ma'am.
はい
じゃあ あんちゃんも
エルルゥたちを頼んだぜ
Okay, Kid, you take care of Eruruu
and her sister too, all right?
In times like this, it's better for them to have
a man around the house they can rely on.
こういう時は
男手があった方が頼もしいわな
Now, Aruruu, you be sure to do what
the kid here says, all right?
アルルゥも ちゃんと
あんちゃんの言うことを聞くんだぜ
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
No!
Get back here, Aruruu!
こら アルルゥ
Why can't you just speak to him politely!?
どうしてちゃんと挨拶できないの？
No!
It seems like she just doesn't like me at all.
どうやら嫌われているらしい
Oh? Is that what you really believe?
さあ 本当にそう思うかい？
ダーッハッハッハッハ
Hey, don't you worry about it, ya hear me!?
まあ 気にすんなって
Okay...
ガアアーッ
It's finally come to this.
どうここまで
Grandma...
おばあちゃん
Just keep still.
ええか じっとしているんじゃぞ
Help me!
-はあっ
-助けてー！
No, stop, or you'll be killed too!
待って あなたも殺されちゃう
But!
しかし
You mustn't! What do you think
you could do anyway?
いかん　行ってどうするつもりじゃ
The master of the forest is not something
we can stand up against.
森の主は わしらが
抗えるものではないのじゃぞ
Even so, I cannot sit by and
let someone else die!
だからといって 見殺しにはできない
You dying in vain would only add to the number
of victims. We can't have that! Please understand!
いたずらに犠牲を増やす訳にはいかんのじゃ
分かっておくれ
Why is this happening, Grandma?
We fixed the shrine properly.
おばあちゃん どうして？
ちゃんとタムヤも直したのに
When I was about Aruruu's age,
まだわしがアルルゥぐらいだった頃
my older sister went into the forest
to make an offering to its master.
姉様が 主様を
お世話するために森に入った
A living sacrifice!?
生贄？
Older sister?
姉様…
As a priestess, my sister
had certain powers,
姉様には カムナギとしての力があってな
and it's thanks to her that we have not
had any incidents up until now.
それで姉様のおかげで
これまで何事も無かったんじゃ
It will be all right, just keep still
and don't make a sound.
大丈夫じゃ
じっと静かにしておったらええ
What are you doing?
おぬし
The sounds have stopped.
音が聞こえなくなった
I'm just going out to see...
確かめて来るだけです
Won't you just wait!?
これ待たんか
グチャ グチャ
グチャ グチャ グチャ
グルル
ガア グルル
ガア ガアアッ
ガアー ガアアッ
ガアッ ガア
だあーっ！
グルル グルルル
Don't!
駄目ーっ！
Eruruu!
エルルゥ
さ つかまってください
Hold onto me.
Forget about it. Run!
駄目だ　逃げろ
No!
嫌です
グルル
Get out of here, Eruruu!
逃げるんだ　エルルゥ
NO!
嫌ーっ！
グルル
What's going on?
Why isn't it coming at us?
どうした
なぜ来ない
グルル グルルルル
Have we been saved?
助かったのか？
It is all right.
-大丈夫だ
-はっ
It went off somewhere else.
あいつはどこかへ行った
We have been saved.
助かったんだよ
無事だったから良かったものの
I'm just glad that you are all right, but still!
You fool!
バカ　うっ うう…
I'm sorry.
すまない
I see, the whole Kirikuri family...
そうかい　キリクリのうちのもんも
The wife and child too!
They were all devoured!
かみさんも子どもも 皆食われちまった
The child was only an infant...
まだ赤ん坊だったのに
What in the world are we going to do?
わしらは 一体どうすれば
Chief!
村長！
Please have a look at this.
これを見てください
What is it, Kid?
あんちゃん
These are Mutikapa's hairs.
これは
ムティカパの毛です
あいつが立ち去ったのは
気まぐれでも何でもない
She did not just go away simply on a whim.
水に濡れるのが嫌だったんだ
It was because she did not want to get wet.
Whoa... That's amazing, Kid!
あ すげえじゃねえか あんちゃん
You didn't put your life on the line
for nothing after all!
体を張った甲斐があったってもんだ
That was still reckless!
だからといって あんな無茶
Please don't ever do that again.
もう絶対しないでください
So?
して
What are you thinking then?
おぬしは何を考えておる
She...
あいつは
Mutikapa...
ムティカパは
You mean there's something we
can do about her, right?
どうにかなるってことだろう？
Yes!
はい
Thing is, we'll hafta band together
or it ain't gonna work.
ただし 皆で力を合わせなきゃ
無理だろうけどな
You mean we're going to kill the master?
俺たちが 主様を？
How could we?
そんなこと
Even if it is the master of the forest,
森の主といえど
there is no reason for you to go on
living in fear like this.
このまま我々が
怯え続ける道理はありません
I understand that we can't let it
go on like this, but...
それは このままって訳には
But still...
けど
Yeah...
なあ？
I will do it.
自分が
I will lure her out.
自分が囮になります
Lure her out?
囮だなんて
どうしてあんなことを言ったんですか？
Why did you say such a thing!?
It would be most appropriate for
an outsider like me to do it.
いや よそ者の自分こそがふさわしい
That's not what I'm talking about!
そういうことを
言ってるんじゃありません
Why do you have to do it?
どうして あなたが…
Because there will not be anyone to
grieve over the loss if I die.
自分なら居なくなっても
悲しむ者は居ないからね
What makes you say things like that?
どうしてそんなことを言うんですか？
あなたは私たちを
Didn't you tell me that we are your family?
家族だって言ってくれたじゃないですか
エルルゥ
Eruruu...
I don't want anyone in my family
to be in danger.
私は家族を
危ない目に遭わせたくありません
I'm sorry. However, I do not intend to
go out there only to be killed.
すまない
だが自分だって やられに行く訳じゃない
But...
だけど…
I will be all right.
大丈夫だ
As long as you are willing to be my family,
I will come back without fail.
自分も君が家族で居てくれる限り
必ず戻るよ
In setting our trap, I think it would be a good
idea to take advantage of this marsh.
罠を作るには
この沼を利用するのがいいと思います
So then we seal off the marsh
without her knowing about it?
そこを分かんねえように
塞いじまえばいい訳か
Once I have lured Mutikapa out,
I want you to cut the rope we rig up.
ムティカパを誘い出したら
仕掛け縄を切ってください
C'mon, Kid!
あんちゃん
心配しないで　上手く逃げますよ
Do not worry, I will escape all right.
But if we destroy the master of the forest...
でも
森の主を退治なんかしたら
Right, we'll curse ourselves!
そうだ　祟りが…
Then will you continue to wait
until its belly is full?
このまま奴の腹が膨れるまで待つのか？
Do you plan to spend night after night in fear?
夜ごと怯え続けるつもりなのか？
Kid...
あ あんちゃん
What he says is true enough.
そりゃそうだな
これ以上子供が食われるのは御免だ
Sorry, but I don't wanna see
any more kids get eaten!
That's right.
そうだね
Yeah, true enough.
-そうだな
-うん
We have to do something!
俺たちの手で
よーし 決まりだ
All right, then it's decided! Why don't you
pick up where you left off, Kid?
あんちゃん 話を続けてくれ
Mutikapa...
ムティカパ
You're a very kind girl, Aruruu.
アルルゥは優しい子じゃな
However...
じゃが
We cannot give up our own lives!
わしらとて生きることを
放棄する訳にはいかんのじゃ
こんなもんか
Like this?
Okay, the rope's set up.
仕掛け縄も張ったぞい
I'll cut the rope.
縄は俺が切る
The rest of you head back.
皆は戻れ
What's the deal? You're risking your
lives if you don't go back!
どうした？　戻らないと危ない
You'd probably get lonely
on your own though.
１人だと心細いだろ
If anything happens, we're
better off in a group.
何かあった時は 大勢の方がいい
You guys are somethin'...
お前ら
It's not right to let that kid be the only one
to put himself in harm's way either.
あのあんちゃんにだけ
危ないことを押し付けるのもな
なあ
Yep!
I will be fine on my own from here on.
ここからは 自分だけで大丈夫です
C'mon, man, don't say that!
まあ そう言うなって
It's not gonna look good on the
men of Yamayura Village
怪我人１人を行かせたとあっちゃあ
男が廃るってもんよ
if we send off a single injured man
to do the job for us.
Teoro-san...
テオロさん
Gee, it feels kinda awkward to be
called by my own name.
なめえで呼ばれっと 照れ臭せえなあ
Actually, I go by "Pops", see?
俺は親父で通ってんだ
So you can call me "Pops", all right?
だからあんちゃんも
俺のことは親父さんでいいからな
But you are hardly old enough
for me to call you that!
そんな年でもないでしょう
It's more 'cuz people are always
countin' on me to do stuff for 'em!
それだけ皆に
頼りにされてるってことだなあ
Not my place to be tootin'
my own horn though!
ま 自分で言うこっちゃねえか
ダッハッハッハッハッハ
Say, Kid...
なあ あんちゃん
Yes?
はい？
Why are you doing all this for us?
何であんたはそんなに
俺たちのためにしてくれるんだ？
For me without my memories,
this place is all I have.
記憶の無い自分にとっては
今はここが全てですから
You're already a respectable
member of our village!
あんちゃんはもう立派な ここの男だよ
そう言っていただけると
Such praise definitely makes me...
Cut it out, will ya?
よせやい 水臭せえ
Jeez, don't be such a stranger!
If you're glad, then just say it straight!
嬉しい時は嬉しいって言うもんだろ
Is this it?
ここか
I'm going in!
行きます
Right!
おう
Has it begun?
始まったか
グル グルル グル
ガアアー
ガウッ
えっ えっ ひい ひい ひい
ガルル ガル
ガルルル ガアッ
ガル ガアアーッ
Good! Her large size makes moving
through here difficult!
いいぞ　奴の巨体では
身動きが取りにくいんだ
ガル ガル
ガルル
Where did she disappear to!?
あいつ どこに消えた？
ガアア
Kid!
あんちゃーん！
ぬあ ああっ
What is this?
これは？
A charm of sorts.
お守りみたいなものじゃ
Take it with you.
持ってお行き
Dirtbag!
野郎ー！
ふんっ
ガルッ
Damn, that thing's hard!
何て固てえんだ
Let's go!
親父さん！
Right!
おう！
ガアアー
I can hear it getting closer.
声が 迫ってる
Here they come!
来るぞ
Hang on, you two...
あんちゃん 俺たち
ガア ガア グルル
Now!
今だ！
うおりゃ！
ガアアーッ
ガアア
ガアアー
うう やったぞ！
We did it!
Take this!
バカ野郎！
ギャオーッ
うりゃーっ！
でけえ  ふう くっ ううあ
Mutikapa-sama...
ムティカパ… 様
フシュー グルル
いやーっ！
ギャオーッ
Welcome home, dear.
お帰り あんた
デッヘッヘッヘ
Well done.
ご苦労だったね
Ma'am...
はい
It saved my life.
命を救われました
It's yours.
それはお前さんの物じゃ
Carry it with you.
持っておくがええ
Grandma!
おばあちゃーん！
What's wrong?
どうしたんじゃ？
I can't find Aruruu anywhere!
アルルゥがどこにも居ないの！
Aruruu!
アルルゥ！
I couldn't find her.
こっちには居ませんでした
Neither could I.
こっちも駄目です
What should we do?
She's not anywhere to be found!
どうしよう　どこにも居ない
It's all right.
大丈夫　ムティカパももう居ないんだ
Mutikapa is no longer around either.
She should not be in any danger.
危険は無いはずだ
But still...
でも…
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
Stop right there!
待ちなさい！
What in the world were you off doing
at a time like this!?
一体こんな時に何してたの
Aruruu, what are you hiding there?
アルルゥ 何を隠してるの？
A baby.
赤ちゃん
Huh!?
アルルゥの赤ちゃん
My baby.
But where could you have...
一体 どこで？
That just can't be!
そんな訳あるはずなかろう
-ミャー
-あ？
Aruruu! What are you really hiding there!?
アルルゥ　本当は何を隠しているの？
ミャー
It's my baby.
アルルゥの赤ちゃん
How cute!
可愛い
That coat of hair! Is that thing Mutikapa or what!?
その毛並み
そいつ ムティカパ様なんじゃねえか？
Mutikapa-sama's...
ムティカパ様の
But what the heck is she
doing with it anyway?
しかし 何だってそんなものを
What happened, Aruruu?
アルルゥ 何があったんじゃ？
Come on now, tell us.
さ 話してみ
Well, I promised.
約束 したから
Promised?
約束？
Now we've got another burden on our hands.
こりゃまた厄介なものを
What do we do?
どうする？
Regardless of what we do,
どうするったって こんな赤ん坊じゃ
親が死んじまったら生きていけねえ
a baby like that won't be able to
live with its parent dead.
And if by some chance it does
manage to survive, then what?
それに万が一 生き延びたりしたら
This one will also develop a tendency
to attack people... maybe?
こいつも人を襲うようになる… か
I do not want to do any more killing.
自分は
もう殺したくない
New lives are born pure.
生まれてくる命は
元来無垢なものだ
That little one has committed no wrongs.
その子供に罪は無い
Well, it's decided then, huh?
うん 決まりだな
ウッフ
ミャーオ
これは ムティカパ様を送る火なんです
This fire is a send-off for Mutikapa.
After all, the only thing we humans
can do is offer prayers like this.
私たち人は
ただこうやって
祈りを送ることしかできないから
ミャーオ
ミャー ミャー
シャーッ
You are its mother.
君が お母さんだ
Father...
お父さん
You mean me!?
自分が？
Father!
お父さん
ミャー
す すいません
あの子 訳の分からないことを
Sorry about her. Sometimes the things
she does don't make any sense.
It's okay, I was glad to hear that.
いや 嬉しかった
It made me glad.
嬉しいと 思えた
That's right, if you're glad, then
just say it straight!
そうだ！
嬉しい時は嬉しいって言うもんだ
ダッハッハ
Oh, Teoro-san, you're drunk!
もう テオロさん酔っぱらって
デーッヘッヘッヘッヘ
Hey, at least lemme have a
few drinks tonight, okay?
今日ぐれえは飲ませてくれって
But you get drunk every night!
毎晩酔っぱらってるじゃないですか
-んっ あ… はあ
-ええい 新しいヤマユラの男に乾ぺえだ！
Hey, here's to Yamayura's new guy!
おう
Yeah, that's for sure!
We really are lucky to have you here!
そうだ そうだ
あんちゃんが居てくれて
ほんと 良かったぜ
Yeah, if it hadn't been for you,
I don't know where we'd be now.
ああ　あんちゃんが居なかったら
どうなっていたことか
Tuskuru-san?
トゥスクルさん
I say it's troublesome for you to go on
without having a real name.
おぬし いつまでも名無しじゃ不便じゃて
From this day forward,
we shall call you Hakuoro.
今日から
ハクオロと名乗るがええ
ハクオロ
Hakuoro...
That's my father's name...
お父さんの
名前
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき　私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Violet and Amber